《綠箭俠》前情提要
Previously, on "Arrow..."
但有些事情永遠不能提起
But there are some things that must never be spoken of.
你怎能不告訴我  馬爾科姆•梅林是我父親
How could you not tell me Malcolm Merlyn was my father?!
莎拉  你不是個殺手
Sara, you're not a killer!
我該是什麼就是什麼
I am what I need to be.
羅伊  你是個危險的人
Roy, you're dangerous.
有些人就是扭曲
Some people are just broken, man.
我不會讓羅伊遇上發生在斯萊德身上的事
I am not letting what happened to Slade happen to Roy.
那是我想的東西嗎
Is that what I think it is?
米拉庫魯  我們要用它製造解藥
Mirakuru. We're going to use it to make a cure.
沒有改變嗎
No change?
沒有
Nope.
好多血和好多米拉庫魯混在一起
So much blood mixed in with so much Mirakuru,
我不知道那是好事還是壞事
I don't know if it's good or bad.
我們真的很需要解藥
We could really use that cure.
我今早和凱特琳聊過了
I talked to Caitlin this morning.
他們在努力
They're working on it.
沒提到伊莎貝爾•羅切夫的死嗎
No mention on Isabel Rochev's death?
完全沒有  我也沒指望有華麗的訃告
Not a thing. I wasn't expecting a glowing obituary,
但她是失蹤一周的福布斯500強總裁
but she's a Fortune 500 CEO that's been missing for a week now.
我還以為她會占點篇幅呢
You'd think she'd have some column inches.
他躺在那我覺得有些害怕
Does the fact that him lying there freaks me out a little
這說明我是個壞人嗎
make me a bad person?
費利西蒂  我覺得世界上沒有什麼力量
Felicity, I don't think there's a force on earth
能讓你變成壞人
that can make you a bad person.
但我餓壞了
But I am starving.
一起吃晚餐嗎
Dinner?
好
Yeah.
但是不去大貝利[大肚]漢堡店
No Big Belly burger, though.
會讓我肚子變大
It's giving me a big belly.
那就吃壽司
Sushi, then.
你都昏迷了怎麼還能嚇我...
How can you be unconscious and freak me out at the same...
一跳啊
time?
羅伊
Roy?
天啊
Oh, my God!
你嚇壞我了
Oh, you scared me.
羅伊
Roy?
忘記拿手機了
Forgot my phone.
羅伊  聽著
Roy, listen--
狄格
Dig!
-你沒事吧  -快去
- You ok? - Go!
羅伊
Roy!
怎麼回事
What's going on?
讓開  讓開  讓開
Move, move, move, move, move, move, move, move!
讓開
Move, move!
綠   箭   俠
第二季 第二十集
你覺得羅伊沒事吧
You think Roy's ok?
別告訴我你現在在想羅伊的事
Please tell me that you're not thinking about Roy right now.
我們終於獨處了  躺在
We're finally alone, in bed,
一家豪華酒店房間裡的床上
in a very nice hotel room.
你付不起這豪華酒店的房費
A hotel room that you couldn't afford.
我和這裡的經理有點關係
I have something of a history with the manager.
我還真是想不到啊
I can only imagine.
我想我有次就是倒的這間房裡的垃圾
I think I trashed this specific room once.
但是特權用完了
But favors run out.
我們該考慮找一個更長久的地方
We should think about getting a more permanent place.
我們
We?
你和勞蕾爾住一起可能也膩了
Well, you're probably getting tired of staying with Laurel,
既然羅伊在鑄造廠
and we can't sleep in the foundry
我們也不能睡在那裡  所以...
now that Roy's there, so...
不過  我是說"我們"
But, I mean, "We,"
你這是讓我搬去和你同居嗎
now you're asking me to move in with you?
你的手機響了
Hey, your phone's ringing.
我知道
I know.
好吧  我倆的手機都在響
Okay, both our phones are ringing,
這從來不是好事
that's never good.
費利西蒂  來電
出什麼事了
What happened?
我不知道  前一分鐘他還昏迷不醒
I don't know. One minute he's comatose,
接下來他就掀翻了電腦設備
the next, he's flipping over computer equipment.
他比斯萊德在你家還失控
He was a lot more out of control than Slade was at your house.
他看起來像羅伊  但他不是羅伊
He looked like Roy, but he...wasn't Roy.
你覺得他要去哪裡
Where do you think he's headed?
我不知道  但我們得找到他
I don't know, but we have to find him.
出乎大家意料之外
Despite everyone's predictions,
你在最近的投票中超過了塞巴斯蒂安•布拉德
you've managed to pull ahead of Sebastian Blood in recent polls.
是的  我們所傳達的信息和選民產生了共鳴
Yes. I think our message is resonating with the voters.
星城人民知道我高瞻遠矚
The people of Starling know that I have a vision,
並擁有經驗豐富的機構  能讓夢想成真
and the experienced apparatus to make that vision a reality.
你覺得人民該給你  而不是布拉德議員
What would you say is the main reason
投票的主要原因是什麼
they should vote for you over Alderman Blood?
這個嘛
Well, um...
布拉德議員沒有孩子
Alderman Blood isn't a parent.
作為父母的重點
And the soul of being a parent
就是保證孩子擁有美好的未來
is making sure that your children have a bright future.
我很幸運  我為我的孩子安排了美好的未來
And I've been very lucky to be able to do that for my own.
是啊  年度最佳母親
Yeah. Mother of the year.
我正在接受採訪呢
Uh, we're in the middle of an interview.
那我長話短說
Oh, I'll keep it short.
你不能在威登酒吧召開集會
You can't have your rally at Verdant.
這是我唯一擁有的未被你荼毒的地方
It's the only place I have that hasn't been poisoned by you.
能讓我們聊會兒嗎
Can you give me one moment, please?
關掉
Turn it off.
西婭  我知道你很生氣
Thea, I know you're upset,
你有理由如此
and you have every right to be,
但我們得去別的地方聊
but we need to talk somewhere else.
我不想跟你聊了  我只是過來告訴你
I'm done talking. I just came by to tell you,
你想用我的酒吧是絕對不可能的事
it'll be a cold day in hell before you can use my club.
我們不能集會前一天突然改變地點
We can't just change the venue the day before.
我肯定你能想出辦法的
I'm sure you can figure something else.
畢竟  你擁有經驗豐富的機構
I mean, you have such an experienced apparatus.
你簽了合同
You signed a contract.
我還以為你的下限不會更低了呢...
Just when I thought you couldn't go any lower...
你竟然威脅你自己的女兒
You threaten your own daughter.
莫伊拉
Moira.
怎麼回事
What's going on?
抱歉讓你看到這些
Sorry you had to witness that.
她被綁架後
After her abduction,
我還以為你倆應該更為親密
I'd think that the two of you would be closer than ever.
情況很複雜
It's a very complicated situation.
我的建議是
Well, my advice?
簡化它
Simplify it.
你要麼做個母親  要麼做候選人
You have to be either a mother or a candidate.
沒法兩全其美
You can't be both.
現在不行  你不能分散注意
Not right now. You cannot split your focus.
你說得太對了
You're absolutely right.
你無精打采時真可愛
You're really cute when you're mopey.
我不是無精打采
I'm not mopey.
無精打采是你的默認狀態  奧利
Mopey's your default, Ollie.
這是你鬱積魅力的一部分
It's part of your smoldering charm.
我的確有鬱積魅力
I do have smoldering charm.
但你比平常更加無精打采
But you're more than usual mopey.
一切都還好嗎
Is everything all right?
沒事
It's fine.
奧利
Ollie.
我和湯米出去玩
Tommy had me out a little bit later
回來的有些晚了
than maybe I should have been, and...
所以我有點累了
I'm wiped.
你想讓我走嗎
Well, you want me to go?
我答應過莎拉要給她輔導三角學的
I promised Sara I'd help her with her trigonometry.
那是什麼東西
I don't know what that is.
你很可愛
You are very cute.
睡一會兒吧
Get some sleep.
再見
Bye.
晚安  奎恩夫人
Good night, Mrs. Queen.
晚安
Good night.
你昨晚沒和湯米一起出去
You didn't go out with Tommy last night.
謝謝你偷聽我的整個談話  媽媽
Thanks for eavesdropping on my entire conversation, Mom.
真好
That's--that's nice.
寶貝  你有煩心事
Sweetheart, something's bothering you,
和我說說
tell me what it is.
爸爸會殺了我的
Dad's going to kill me.
你父親是愛你的
Your father loves you.
我愛你
I love you.
我搞砸了
I screwed up.
很糟糕
It's bad.
怎麼回事
What happened?
我讓一個女孩懷孕了
I got a girl pregnant.
勞蕾爾懷孕了
Laurel's pregnant?
沒有
No.
不是勞蕾爾
Not Laurel.
這太荒唐了
This is ridiculous.
我們不能就這麼到處瞎逛
We can't just ride around all night
指望能找到他
hoping to lay eyes on him.
-狄格爾  -他不在住處
- Diggle? - His place is clean.
我認為他不會回去
I don't think he's been back here.
有個電話召急救車去14大街和霍巴特路路口
Call just went out for an ambulance at 14th and Hobart.
有四個人遭到一個
There's four men seriously assaulted...
14大街與霍巴特路路口
穿紅色兜帽衫人的襲擊
by someone wearing a red hoodie.
發生了什麼
What happened?
那傢伙突然冒出來  直接就來打我們
Guy jumped us. Came out of nowhere.
那傢伙跟打了雞血一樣
The dude is 'roided out or something.
瘋狂得很
Crazy like.
再會  辛
See ya, Sin.
再見[西語]
Adios.
小屁孩
Yo, Abercrombie.
等等  你去哪了
Hold up. Where you been, man?
我去找過你差不多20次了
I went over to your place like 20 times.
西婭說你去外地了
Thea said you skipped town.
我去
Holy crap.
你打架了嗎
Have you been in a fight?
辛  這傢伙在找你麻煩嗎
Sin, is this guy bothering you?
不  他很冷靜  真的  你走開吧
No, no, no, he's chill. Seriously, just step off.
有什麼問題嗎
We going to have a problem, guy?
你真要這麼著嗎
Seriously?
別管他  他沒事
Just leave him alone, he's fine.
怎麼  慫了不說話了
Oh, what, you got nothing smart to say?
費利西正在蒂通過遍佈全城的
Felicity's running facial recognition
監控攝像頭進行面部識別
on traffic cameras throughout the city.
也許永遠都完不成
Which could take forever.
在羅伊傷害其他人之前我們必須把他打倒
We need to take Roy down now before he attacks any more people.
"我不想見到你這句話"
What part of "I want nothing to do with you"
哪個字你聽不懂
are just not understanding?
我是來找莎拉的
I came by to see Sara.
那他呢
And what about him?
他在跟蹤我
He's been stalking me.
他在保護你
He's protecting you.
因為什麼呢
From what?
斯萊德•威爾遜還沒被抓到
Slade Wilson is still at large.
他已經嘗試過傷害你了
He already tried hurting you once.
他沒有傷到我
He didn't hurt me.
他告訴了我真相  你認為是壞事的真相
He told me the truth, which I know you think is a bad thing,
其實不是壞事
but it's actually not.
如果意味著我要失去你那就是
It is if it costs me you.
你的謊言才是
Your lies did that.
現在  我要去樓上的儲藏室
Now, I'm going to go upstairs to the stock room,
如果有人拿小酒杯打我
and if I get attacked by some shot glasses,
我自己會報警的
I'll call 911.
謝謝你照顧她
Thanks for taking care of her.
幸運的是  她不像你那麼善於消失
Lucky for me, she's not as good at disappearing as you were.
我去去就回
I'll be right back.
你見到西婭了嗎
Have you seen Thea?
你眼睛怎麼了
What happened to your eye?
沒什麼  化個妝掩蓋一下就好
It's ok. I could cover it with make-up.
如果我有那手藝的話
If I work make-up.
沒事的
It's fine.
誰幹的
Who did this to you?
說來話長
It's a long story.
我問你是誰幹的
I asked you who.
羅伊
Roy.
他現在腦子不正常
But he's not right in the head.
他被人注射了什麼東西
He got injected with something.
也許是藥吧  但那讓他變得很強壯
A drug, I don't know, but it made him strong.
就像  漫畫裡的英雄那樣
Like, comic book strong.
我知道那聽上去很瘋狂
Look, I know it sounds nuts--
其實不會
It really doesn't.
莎拉  羅伊是個朋友
Sara, Roy's a friend.
他需要幫助  而不是被打
He needs help, not a beat down.
我等會給你回電話
I'll have to call you right back.
我需要留下嗎  布拉德先生
Do you want me to stay, Mr. Blood?
不用  謝謝你
No, thank you.
沒事的
I'll be fine.
我的新保鏢
My new body man.
他有點擔心過頭
He's a little over-protective.
-請坐  -不用  謝謝
- Please. - No, thank you.
不得不說你的來訪有點突然
I'd say this visit is unexpected,
但我會有什麼說什麼
but I despise understatements.
我要退出競選了
I'm dropping out of the race.
我會在今晚的集會上發布敗選演說
I'm making a concession speech at my rally tonight.
上一輪投票後你是領先的
You're ahead in the latest polls.
即便是持最懷疑態度的專家
Even the most skeptical pundits
都說你很可能勝出
are saying you could actually pull this out.
我是出於禮貌才當面告訴你這事的
I felt I owed you the courtesy of informing you in person.
但我不需要向你解釋什麼
I don't, however, owe you an explanation as well.
是的  你說得對
No, you don't.
但是我希望你解釋一下
But I'd appreciate one.
無論你是要做什麼事  莫伊拉
What you're doing, Moira,
只要會給我帶來好處
as much as it benefits me,
似乎都不合常理
doesn't really make much sense.
是為了我的女兒
It's my daughter.
這個時候  她比星城更需要我
At the moment, she needs me more than Starling does.
你做了正確的事
Well, you're doing the right thing.
我要改變這座城市  莫伊拉
I'm going to change this city, Moira.
新的時代即將開啟
A new day is coming.
一個更好的時代
A better day.
對我們所有人
For all of us.
我知道有些事情讓人喪氣  寶貝
I know things seem bleak, sweetheart,
但我們會解決的  我保證
but we're going to figure this out, I promise.
媽媽  這公平嗎
Mom, does it seem fair?
犯了
To make...
一個錯誤  那感覺
one mistake, and it...
就好像我的整個生命已經結束了
feels like my entire life is over.
你的生活才沒有完蛋
Oh, your life is far from over.
你確定孩子是你的嗎
Are you sure it's yours?
只要你有錢  奧利弗
Where there is money, Oliver,
就會有人想來占你的便宜
there are people looking to take advantage.
她不是那種人  她是個好人  媽媽
She's not that type of person. She's a good person, Mom.
她是...
She's...
好吧
All right.
我不知道該怎麼辦  我該怎麼辦呢
I don't know what to do. What do I do?
人非聖賢孰能無錯  奧利弗  我希望
We all make mistakes, Oliver. And I had hoped
有天你也會原諒我所犯下的錯誤
that one day you'd forgive me for any that I might make, so...
好了  我出去下
All right, um, I'll be right back.
辛在威登酒吧  14街和霍巴特街路口
Verdant, 14th and Hobart,
還有另一個酒吧都有看到他
and the bar Sin spotted him at.
-他好像正往東走  -東邊有什麼
- He looks to be moving east. - What's east?
奎恩家的豪宅
Queen mansion.
如果他還記得西婭的住處
If he still remembers where Thea lives--
以前的住處
well, used to live,
但羅伊並不知道...
but Roy doesn't know that...
或許他的人性並沒有完全泯滅
There might be something in Roy still left in there.
或許他只是碰巧往東走而已
Or it's just a coincidence that he's moving east.
我知道這件事牽扯到了辛
Ahem. I know that Sin's involved,
但不要讓它影響你的判斷
but don't let that cloud your judgment.
別忘了以前羅伊可是經常影響你的判斷
Well, don't let the fact that this used to be Roy cloud yours.
辛
Sin.
我找到羅伊了
I found Roy.
我跟你說了回家去
Well, I thought I told you to go home.
是的  我就在家這兒呢
Yeah, that's where I am right now.
還有他
And so is he.
羅伊
Roy!
他不在這兒
He's not here.
我是奧利弗
It's Oliver.
是我啊
It's me.
你現在之所以這樣
What you're doing right now,
全都是因為米拉庫魯
it's because of the Mirakuru.
你是個好人  羅伊
You're a good person, Roy.
你的良知和靈魂還在
You have a conscience and a soul.
利用這些來頑強抗爭  你能做到的
I need you to use those and fight this. You can do it!
把箭放下  放下
Drop the arrow, drop it!
不要
No!
今晚滿月
A full moon tonight.
所以稀奇古怪的事更可能發生
That really brings out the whack jobs.
好消息是不可能會有更怪的事發生了
Good news is, it can't get any stranger.
我的朋友需要你的幫助
My friend needs your help.
看來我錯了  我再打給你
I was wrong. Got to call you back.
有些是舊傷復發
Some of this damage is chronic.
我猜是從屋頂上跳下來而引發的
The cost of jumping off rooftops, I guess.
我要趕快恢復
I need to get back on my feet.
我可以給你個支架
I can give you a brace,
但你走起路來還是會很痛
but you'll still be in horrendous amounts of pain.
六個月前  這個藥櫃面臨清空的危險
Six months ago, this cabinet would have been empty.
華人三合會想阻礙我們的藥品運輸船
The Chinese Triad was stopping all of our med shipments--
後來有個人阻止了他們
until someone stopped them.
從那之後  我一直想找個機會謝謝你
Ever since, I've been looking for a way to thank you.
威登酒吧
如果你非要到處跟著我
If you're going to have to follow me everywhere,
至少別躲著  好嗎
at least don't lurk, all right?
我必須盯著你
I can't let you out of my sight.
你不喜歡去哪兒都見到我
You're sick of seeing me everywhere you go;
躲著似乎是個不錯的折中辦法
lurking seemed like a good compromise.
效果不太好啊
Yeah, well, it's not.
家人間和諧相處很難
Family's hard.
有時他們是世界上最難相處的
Sometimes they're the hardest in the world.
相親相愛  團團圓圓
Loving someone so much and letting them love you back.
你說得對  你還是回去躲著比較好
You know, you're right... You should go back to lurking.
我經常跟你家人待在一起
I've spent a lot of time with your family.
如果這樣你就覺得能插手我的事了
If you think that gives you the right to weigh in,
你就大錯特錯了
you're wrong.
再說了  奧利弗很快就成窮光蛋了
Plus, Oliver will be out of money soon
你也會失業的
and you'll be unemployed.
可不是
Right.
趁我失業前我得趕緊勸勸你
I guess I should get this in under the wire.
你媽媽並不完美
You know, your mother isn't perfect.
經常犯錯
Her judgment definitely isn't.
但她唯一始終如一的就是
But there's one thing she's consistent about
她愛你和奧利弗
is that she loves you and Oliver.
那你覺得這應該為她贏得什麼嗎
And that should buy her what in your mind?
我不知道  西婭
Well, I don't know, Thea...
但她是你的母親
But she is your mother.
總該有點兒分量吧
That should buy her something.
要不再給她次機會吧
A second chance, maybe.
全市通緝一名罪犯
...A citywide man hunt for the perpetrator of an attack
他造成一名警員重傷
that left one police officer seriously injured
一名警員死亡
and the other dead.
我們將播放旁觀者錄制的現場視頻
We have video shot by a bystander,
但提醒某些觀眾
but please be warned that the
重大新聞
影像甚是清晰
footage may be too graphic for some viewers.
我的天吶
Oh, my God.
西婭
Thea...
我要去見個朋友
I have to go see a friend.
如果你非要跟  那就跟吧
If you have to follow, follow.
這些可不會讓你膝蓋好起來
These aren't going to fix your knee.
它們會讓膝蓋好得快一點
They'll help it heal faster.
那痊癒之前呢
And until then?
面部識別有什麼進展嗎
Where are we with facial recognition?
交通攝像頭拍得不清楚
Traffic cams can't get a clear shot.
現在我知道你戴兜帽的原因了
Now I see why you wear that hood.
無人匹配
費利西蒂  我們要先找到他
Felicity... We need to find Roy before the police do.
因為員警找到他後會殺了他  而我們不會嗎
Because they'll kill him and we won't?
尖端科研實驗室正在研究解藥
S.T.A.R. Labs is working on a cure.
或許他們永遠都研究不出來
Which they may never come up with.
即便有解藥了  但在這期間
And even if they do, I mean, how many people
得會有多少人死在羅伊手上
are we going to let Roy kill in the meantime?
你本來也想殺了海倫娜
You know, you wanted to kill Helena, too.
但你找到別的方法了
You found another way.
這是兩回事  你心知肚明
That was different, and you know it.
羅伊體內有米拉庫魯  跟斯萊德一樣
Roy has the Mirakuru in him, just like Slade.
如果現在你有機會殺死斯萊德
And if you had a clear shot of Slade right now,
你一定會下手
you would take it.
羅伊不是斯萊德
Roy isn't Slade!
羅伊不是羅伊了
Roy isn't Roy.
他已經不是他自己了
He's not himself anymore,
無法挽救了
he's too far gone.
我不相信
I don't believe that.
你知道你在說些什麼嗎  奧利
Do you even hear yourself right now, Ollie?
五年前我們就有過一模一樣的對話
This is the exact conversation that we had five years ago,
唯一不同是那時我們在煉獄島上快凍死了
except we were freezing on Lian Yu.
你在做什麼
What are you doing?
做該做的
What needs to be done.
一槍爆頭  米拉庫魯也救不了他
The Mirakuru won't do anything against a head shot.
莎拉
Sara!
你母親的集會半小時後就會開始
Your mother's rally starts in a half an hour.
我要是你就趕快開始打扮了
I'd start getting dressed if I were you.
她讓我想起我剛回來的時候
She reminds me so much of me after I came home.
一切都看起來...
When it just seemed...
什麼都不相信  甚至是希望
Seemed impossible to believe in anything even resembling hope.
但你相信了
But you did.
你相信了
You did.
最終還是相信了
Eventually.
莎拉也會的
Sara will, too.
謝謝你能來
Oh, thanks for coming.
今天很冷
It's chill.
那是誰
Who's that?
我
I...
我的影子
my shadow.
聽著  羅伊有點兒不對勁
Listen, something is going on with Roy.
我知道  我見過他  他徹底瘋了
I know, I saw him. He's totally crazed.
他到底怎麼了
What's happening to him?
你還記得聖誕節他放我們鴿子那次嗎
Do you remember around Christmas when he bailed on us?
怎麼了
Yeah?
他被注射了一種藥
He got shot up with something, this drug,
這種藥讓他神志不清
and it's been messing with his head.
你和我哥哥說過這件事嗎
Did you tell my brother any of this?
沒有  為什麼這麼問
No...why?
那是他派來盯著我的保鏢
He's got this bodyguard all over me.
他肯定清楚羅伊的事
He must know about Roy,
以為羅伊是想找我還是什麼
think he's coming after me or something.
你打算怎麼辦
Well, what are you going to do?
羅伊
Roy?
羅伊  是我
Roy, it's me.
我是西婭
It's Thea.
真高興我找到你了
I'm so glad I found you.
我一直到處找你
I've been looking everywhere.
這都是我的錯
This is all my fault.
因為我你才變成這樣
I did this to you.
你和我分手是因為你需要幫助
When you broke up with me, it was a cry for help,
可是我沒有聽你解釋
and I didn't listen.
我真該受到懲罰
I should be punished.
我活該受到懲罰
I deserve to be punished.
如果別人傷害到你
Someone hurts you,
你就要傷害他們更深
and you hurt them worse.
要無休止地傷害他們
You hurt them permanently.
你應該殺了我
You should just kill me.
殺了我
Kill me.
奧利弗你去哪了  你接到我的電話了嗎
Oliver, where have you been? Haven't you got any of my calls?
我剛才沒時間  怎麼了
I've been busy. What's wrong?
是你媽媽
It's your mother.
她會沒事的
She'll do fine.
不  她不會
No, she won't.
這次活動不是為了集結大家
She's not using this event to rally the troops.
她是想利用這次機會
She's using it...
告訴大家她要退出競選
to tell people she's dropping out of the race.
奧利弗
Oliver.
發生什麼了
What happened?
摩托車事故
It's a motorcycle accident,
是我大意了
it was stupid.
沒錯  如果我算的沒錯
Yes, this would be the second accident in as many weeks,
這是幾周以來的第二次事故了
if my math is correct.
馬克說你要退出競選
Mark says you're dropping out of the race.
其實我幾個禮拜之前就該就這麼做
The truth is, I should have done it weeks ago,
在西婭被綁架之後
after Thea was abducted.
我的全部心思應該放在修復我們的關係上
My complete focus needs to be on repairing our relationship.
媽媽  西婭現在的情形
Mom, what's happening with Thea right now
不是你沒花時間陪她造成的
isn't because you weren't spending enough time with her.
也許不是吧  但是我必須做點兒什麼
Well, maybe not. I have to do something
我不知道除了這個我還能做什麼
and I'm not sure what else to do.
西婭恨你是因為你過去做的那些事
Thea hates you right now because of the things that you've done.
那些糟糕的事
Terrible things.
所以讓她看到你做些好事
So let her see you do something good.
作為一位市長
As mayor.
媽媽  我瞭解一些事
Mom, I know a little something about...
例如為了這個城市
sacrificing the people closest to me
犧牲我身邊最親近的人
for the good of this city.
這就是你現在應該做的
It's what you need to do now.
我知道
I know.
很好
Good.
奧利弗  我知道
Oliver, I know.
我知道
I know.
我想
I've known...
從去年開始我就知道了
since last year, I suppose.
那個計劃實施的那天
The night of the undertaking,
所有謎題都解開了
everything became so clear.
也是從那天開始我晚上再也睡不著
It was pretty much the night I stopped sleeping.
在你想說什麼之前
Before you say anything else--
我不想說什麼
There's nothing else to say.
我不需要說什麼
Nothing I need to say.
除了告訴你我感到無比驕傲
Except I could not be more proud.
你要喝點什麼嗎
Can I have the raise get you anything to drink?
或者吃些東西  這邊請
Or--or something to eat, perhaps? Please.
奧利弗在哪
Where's Oliver?
他去替我辦事了
Ah, he's...running an errand for me.
剛好我們可以有機會聊一聊
I thought it would give us a chance to talk.
無意冒犯  奎恩夫人
With all due respect, um, Mrs. Queen,
這是我和奧利弗之間的事
what's happening, it's between me and your son.
當然了
Yes.
那是什麼
What is that?
我的調查員給我的一份關於你的檔案
Oh, I had one of our investigators write up a dossier on you.
抱歉  但是預防
I'm sorry, but it's a necessary
欺詐性親權索賠是非常有必要的
precaution against a fraudulent claim of paternity.
孩子是奧利弗的
Well, the baby is Oliver's.
我對此毫不懷疑
Oh, of that I have no doubt.
我們的調查員調查得很全面
Our investigators were quite thorough.
但是你能想像到
But you can imagine
外面有多少人等著
how many people my family attracts
把我們家的事登上新聞
who are looking for handouts.
我不是為了錢
Well, I'm not looking for money.
當然不是
Of course not.
我說了我不想要錢
I told you, I don't want money.
那我告訴你
And I'm telling you
這是我第一次當奶奶
that this is my first grandchild.
我想要確保這個孩子有一個美好的未來
And I want to make certain that he or she has a bright future.
請收下吧
Please.
這有一百萬
This is a million dollars.
我同樣也希望我兒子有一個美好的未來
I want to make certain that my son has a bright future as well.
這一百萬給你
That money is yours
前提是你告訴奧利弗孩子沒了
once you tell Oliver that you've lost the baby.
你說什麼
What?!
等你回中央城後再也不要聯繫他
And another million when you return to Central city,
我會再給你一百萬
never to speak to him again.
我可以給你一個建議嗎
Can I offer you some advice,
以一位母親的身份告誡另一位母親
one mother to another?
一旦事情涉及到你自己的孩子
When it comes to your children, there is no action
沒有什麼事情是你做不出來的
that is inconceivable;
也沒有什麼決定是你下不了的
there is no decision that is impossible.
你會奮不顧身給他他所需要的生活
You do what you must to provide the life that they need.
所以我認為那二百萬美元
And I think that $2 million
可以給我們的孩子提供他們所需要的生活
is sufficient to provide the life that both our children need.
你覺得呢
Don't you?
支持奎恩競選市長
當我最初決定參加此次競選時
When I was first approached about entering this race,
我覺得競選成功的機會是如此渺茫
the prospect of winning seemed a distant,
是幾乎不可能的事
nearly impossible feat.
一個遭受重創的城市
Now, how could a city that had suffered so much
怎麼可能寄希望於給它帶來創傷的人
place its faith in someone so responsible for its suffering?
但是這幾個星期以來
But as the weeks progressed,
那些如你們一樣正直的人
good people such as you
表明了你們的態度
raised your voices
支援我  於是我想我可以讓這座城市更美好
in support, and I began to think that I could make a difference.
我可以為拯救這座城市出一份力
I could help save this city.
莫伊拉•奎恩支持者聚會
但
But...
最近發生的一些事改變了這一切
recent events have changed things, and...
不過現在我確信我可以讓這座城市更美好
and now I know I can make a difference.
如果我能有幸當選市長
And should the honor become mine,
我鄭重地向各位保證
I promise with every breath I take
莫伊拉•奎恩支持者聚會
為了這座城市的美好未來
To do what is necessary,
我將不惜一切代價  不顧一切犧牲
To sacrifice what is necessary for the good of this city.
星城是我的家  你們都是我的家人
Starling City is my home, you are my family,
對我來說沒有什麼比家人更重要
And there is nothing more important to me than family.
謝謝大家
Thank you, thank you all.
說得太好了  莫伊拉
Great speech, Moira.
雖然跟我中意的相差有些遠
A little too off-book for my liking,
但我們會努力的
But we'll work on that.
我覺得很好
I thought it was perfect.
我想上來說幾句
I just wanted to come up here and say a few words.
今晚我很高興我母親能來
I am so proud to have my mom here tonight
我這間貧民區的威登酒吧
at my club, Verdant, in the Glades.
她在幹什麼
What is she doing?
她知道這是直播
She knows this is being televised.
她這是想引羅伊出來
She's sending a message to Roy, trying to draw him out.
請為奎恩投票  跟你們的朋友也這麼說
So vote Queen. Tell your friends.
謝謝
Thanks.
西婭
Thea.
我不是為了你
That was not for you.
天吶  你真沉
Oh, God, you're heavy.
真的都是肌肉的重量嗎
Is this really all muscle?
我們還有多少支毒箭
How many of those venom arrows do we have?
-大約20支  -我全都要帶上
- About 20. - I need all of them.
好吧  你確定這樣做好嗎
Okay. Are you sure that's a good idea?
你膝蓋現在這樣還能穿上戰袍嗎
Can you even get into those leather pants with that knee?
馬上給我利多卡因
Lidocaine. Now.
一種局部麻醉劑
我看一下  上面寫著合適的劑量是
Let's see, the bottle says the proper dose is...
全部
Is all of it.
我覺得這樣不...
I don't think that's a good...
說得太棒了  莫伊拉
Terrific speech, Moira.
我們幾年前就應該推選你
How did we not think of running you years ago?
謝謝
Thank you.
我能失陪一會嗎
Can you give me a moment?
當然
Of course.
你好
Oh, hello.
-你得離開了  -不不不
- You need to go now! - No, no, no!
我不能丟下我女兒
I can't leave without my daughter!
我會保護好你女兒的
I'll see to the safety of your daughter!
走  西婭  我們得離開了
Go, go! Thea, we have to go now!
不  是羅伊
No, it's Roy!
我不會離開他  他為我而來
I'm not leaving him! He came here for me!
羅伊
Roy.
羅伊  聽我說
Roy, listen to me!
好好聽我說
Listen to my voice!
我不知道你是怎麼了
I don't know what's going on with you,
但我堅信我深愛的那個人
but I have to believe the man I fell in love with
他還活著
is still inside there, somewhere.
你要反抗  你很堅強
You have to fight. You're strong.
你能反抗的  你要反抗
You can fight this. Fight this!
羅伊
Roy!
把她放下
Put her down.
不要殺他
Please don't..
他也控制不了
he can't control it.
所以我也沒有辦法
That's why I don't have a choice.
閃開
Get out of the way.
別這樣
Don't do this.
殺了我
Kill me.
求你了
Please.
殺了我
Kill me.
千萬不要殺他
Please don't do it!
今晚誰都不會死
No one dies tonight.
但是員警會...
But he police...
出去
Go outside.
我們會幫助羅伊
We'll get Roy the help he needs.
我保證  快走
I promise! Go!
西藏蝮蛇毒
Tibetan pit viper venom.
常用劑量對他來說沒用  對吧
A constant dose of that can't be good for you. Right?
他會像當初斯萊德那樣昏迷
It'll keep him sedated like it did Slade.
昏迷到什麼時候
Until when?
我們要是用完毒劑了怎麼辦
And what happens when we run out?
這又不是非處方藥
It's not like you can buy this stuff over the counter.
要是在西藏的話  可能可以買到
Unless you're in Tibet. Then...maybe.
我們要照顧好他
We'll take care of him.
我不想放棄羅伊
I'm not ready to give up on Roy.
大戰一場之後有誰想吃點東西嗎
Anyone else crave dim sum after fisticuffs?
都不吃  好吧
No? Ok.
那我就把餃子都吃了
Dumplings for one, then.
我本來要殺他的
I would have killed him.
我已經準備好了
I was ready to.
如果不是你攔著  他現在已經死了
He'd be dead right now if you wouldn't have stopped me.
可他現在沒死
But he's not.
這才是關鍵
That's all that matters.
你說的不對
That's not true.
我想殺死他
I wanted to kill roy.
因為這才是我該做的
Because that's what I do.
這才是我的本性
That's who I am.
我在煉獄中生活了六年
I spent six years in the darkness.
我看著惡魔的雙眼
And I looked into the eyes of the devil
把我的靈魂交給了他
and I gave him my soul.
讓我幫你找回你的靈魂
Let me help you get it back.
不  你應該找個更好的人
No, you deserve someone better.
能夠理解你內心深處的人
Someone who can harness that light that's still inside of you.
但那個人不是我
But I'm not that person.
永遠都不會是我
And I never will be.
莎拉
Sara...
不要
Don't.
對不起
I'm sorry.
我太在乎你了  所以不能跟你在一起
I just care about you too much to be with you.
一切都還好嗎
Everything OK?
是的  只是這一天太不順了
Yeah. Just had a long day.
羅伊怎麼樣了
How's Roy?
他還活著
Well, he's alive,
不用謝我
No thanks to me.
你敢擋在我面前真的很勇敢
You know, that was brave getting between us.
-這需要很大的勇氣  -也未必
- It took guts. - Not really.
我知道你不是真想傷害他
I knew you wouldn't really hurt him.
你不是殺手
You're not a killer.
這是什麼意思
What's this for?
告別
Say good-bye.
什麼  等一下  你要去哪
What? Wait, where are you going?
去見個老朋友
To see an old friend.
這座城市所有的員警都出動了
We've got every cop in this city canvassing.
-我們會找到這個人的  -謝謝
- We'll find this guy. - Thank you.
你還好嗎
You OK?
還行
Fine.
你去哪了
Where were you?
跟我在一起
He was with me.
你們倆和好真是太好了
Glad to see the two of you are getting along again.
西婭
Thea...
羅伊的事你早就知道
You knew about Roy.
什麼
What?
所以你才讓你的保鏢跟蹤我
That's why you had your bodyguard stalking me.
你知道他到底是怎麼回事
Somehow, you knew what was going on with him.
我是想保護你
I'm just trying to protect you.
通過不告訴我真相來保護我嗎
By not telling me the truth.
就跟馬爾科姆•梅林的事一樣
Just like with Malcolm Merlyn.
知道嗎  你們兩個
You know, the two of you,
你們以為有事瞞著我  跟我說謊
you think you're protecting me by lying
就是保護我
and by keeping secrets.
但其實那樣才最傷害我
But that's what's actually hurting me.
你說得很對
You're absolutely right.
我們需要走出過去重新開始
We need to turn a new page.
沒那麼簡單
It's not going to be that simple.
也沒那麼容易
Or easy.
我知道  如果真相於我而言容易的話
I know. If the truth were easy for me,
我們就不會陷入現在這種境地了
we wouldn't be in this situation.
但首先
But to start...
你和奧利弗都需要知道一件
there's something about Malcolm that both you and Oliver
關於馬爾科姆的事
need to know.
馬爾科姆...
Malcolm...
奧利弗
Oliver!
我得死
I need to die.
奧利弗
Oliver!
上次你讓我選擇的時候
I was dead the last time
我選擇了死亡
you were offered this choice.
斯萊德
Slade...
奧利弗
Oliver...
這是怎麼回事
What's happening?
我一直想知道...
I often wonder how you looked...
他用槍指著莎朵把她從我身邊奪走時
when he pointed the gun at Shado...
你是什麼表情
and took her from me.
你個變態
You psychopath.
莎朵  莎朵不是你的
Shado...Shado wasn't yours!
對  她曾經是你的
No, she was yours.
可是後來你選了別的女人沒選她
Until you chose another woman over her.
不是這樣的
That's not what happened!
就是這樣  就是
It is what happened! It is!
她告訴我的
She told me!
你說她是什麼意思  那裡根本沒人
What do you mean, she? There's nobody there!
斯萊德
Slade...
當時你也跟奧利弗一起在島上嗎
You were on the island with Oliver?
我開始以為自己知道什麼是真正的絕望
I thought I had known true despair,
直到後來遇到了你兒子
until I met your son.
我信任他...
I trusted him...
會做出正確的選擇
to make the right choice.
現在讓我做出正確的選擇吧
Let me make the right choice now.
殺我吧
Kill me.
-不  -不要
- NO! - NO!
殺我吧  求你了
Choose me, please!
我會殺你的  奧利弗
I am killing you, Oliver.
不過不會先殺你
Only more slowly than you would like.
不要
Don't.
選吧
Choose.
-不要  -選吧
- Don't-- - Choose.
求你了
Please...
快選
Choose!
我對天發誓  我一定會殺了你
I swear to God, I am going to kill you!
不  不要
No! No!
不
No.
媽...
Mom...
不
No!
媽  你幹什麼
Mom, what are you doing?
要結束今晚
There's only one way
-只有一個辦法  -不要
- this night can end. - No!
求你了  不要
Please don't.
我們都知道是什麼辦法
And we both know that.
是不是  威爾遜先生
Don't we, Mr. Wilson?
媽  求你了  不要
Mom! Please, don't!
不要殺我的孩子
Both my children will live.
媽
Mom!
你幹什麼
What are you doing?!
媽
Mom!
西婭  我愛你
Thea, I love you.
閉上眼睛  孩子
Close your eyes, baby!
不要
No!
你擁有真正的勇氣
You possess true courage.
真的很抱歉
I am truly sorry...
什麼
What?
可是你的勇氣沒有
You did not pass that on
傳給你兒子
to your son.
不
No!
這件事結束之前
There is still one person
還有一個人
who has to die...
必須得死
before this can end.
不要
No!
媽
Mom?
媽  不
Mom! No!
不  媽
No! Mom!
對  我也很抱歉
Well, yeah, I'm sorry, too.
如果有什麼我可以幫忙的話...
Well, listen, if there's ever anything that I can do--
喂
Hello?
是誰
Who was that?
是...
That was, um...
她失去了孩子
She lost the baby.
她說自己很傷心
She said she's sad about it,
要回中心區的學校去了
and she's going to go back to school in central city.
她在那邊肯定有家人
Apparently she has family there.
她肯定很痛苦
Well, I'm sure this has been very traumatic for her.
但這樣對她也許是最好的
But it sounds for the best.
-是啊  -你沒事吧
- Sure. - You OK?
沒事  沒事
Yeah. Yes.
我仍然是世界上最幸運的人
I continue to be the luckiest guy on the planet.
要是...
What...
我該怎麼辦啊  要是...
What would I have done if she...
我還沒做好當爸爸的準備
I'm not ready to be a dad.
現在沒有  但總有一天會的
No. But someday.
這是我最大的希望
It's my fondest hope for you.
我很高興我告訴你了
I'm glad I told you.
要是你不在我身邊
I don't think that I could have
我一個人肯定不知道怎麼辦
gotten through something like this without you.
我會一直在你身邊的
You're never without me.
我的乖兒子
My beautiful boy.
媽...
It's, uh...
我愛你
I love you.